<!--
~ Copyright 2005-2007 WSO2, Inc. (http://wso2.com) ~ ~ Licensed under
the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License"); ~ you may not use
this file except in compliance with the License. ~ You may obtain a
copy of the License at ~ ~ http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
~ ~ Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
software ~ distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS"
BASIS, ~ WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express
or implied. ~ See the License for the specific language governing
permissions and ~ limitations under the License.
-->
<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.1//EN"
        "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml11/DTD/xhtml11.dtd">
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
	<body>
		<h1>ESB Proxy Service Sample</h1>
		<br></br>
		<p>Developer Studio can be used effecetively to work with WSO2 Enterprice Service Bus (ESB) for visual editing of Sequence definitions, Endpoint definitions, Proxy service definitions as well as whole Synapse configurations. 
		In this guide we will show you, how you can use <strong>Developer Studio IDE</strong> to do the <a href="http://wso2.org/project/esb/java/3.0.1/docs/quickstart_guide.html#Proxy">ESB Proxy Service</a> example.</p>
		<h2>Content</h2>
		<div class="toc">
			<ul>
				<li>
					<a href="#CreatingaCarbonApplicationProject">Creating a Carbon Application Project.</a>
				</li>
				<li>
					<a href="#CreatingaProxyServiceUsingDeveloperStudioIDE">Creating a <strong>Proxy Service</strong> using <strong>Developer Studio IDE</strong>.</a>
				</li>
				<li>
					<a href="#AddingaWSO2CarbonBasedServertotheDeveloperStudioIDE">Adding a <strong>WSO2 Carbon Based Server</strong> to the <strong>Developer Studio IDE</strong>.</a>
				</li>
				<li>
					<a href="#StartingtheWSO2CarbonBasedServerfromtheDeveloperStudioIDE">Starting the <strong>WSO2 Carbon Based ESB</strong> from the <strong>Developer Studio IDE</strong>.</a>
				</li>
				<li>
					<a href="#DeployingthecretedProxyServiceintheserverinstanceusingDeveloperStudioIDE">Deploying the creted <strong>Proxy Service</strong> in the server instance using <strong>Developer Studio IDE.</strong></a>
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
		<h2 id="CreatingaCarbonApplicationProject">Creating a Carbon Application Project</h2>		
		<p>
        To create a Carbon Application Project (CApp), right click on the Project Explorer and select <strong>New => Other </strong> from the 
        menu or Select <strong>File => New => Other </strong>. You can also click the <strong>New</strong> button on the toolbar.</p> 
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Creating a Carbon Application Project" src="images/samples/esb/creatingproject1.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
		</p>
		<p>
		Select <strong>Carbon Application Project</strong> and select <strong>Next</strong>
		</p>
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Creating a Carbon Application Project" src="images/samples/esb/creatingproject2.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
		</p>
		<!--<ol>
			<li>New Sequence</li>
			<li>Import Sequence from File System</li>
			<li>Import Sequence from Registry</li>
		</ol>
		-->
		<p>
			Type a name for your Project and click on <strong>Finish</strong>.
		</p>
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Creating a Carbon Application Project" src="images/samples/esb/creatingproject3.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
		</p>
		
		<p>
			If you have successfully completed the project creation process, your Developer Studio will look like similar to this.
		</p>
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Creating a Carbon Application Project" src="images/samples/esb/creatingproject4.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
		</p>

			
			<h2 id="CreatingaProxyServiceUsingDeveloperStudioIDE">Creating a Proxy Service using Developer Studio IDE</h2>
			<br></br>
			<p>Here, we are going go create a Proxy Service using Developer Studio. Proxy Service is one of the <strong>Artifacts</strong> that can be deployed on ESB.
			You can add <strong>Artifacts</strong> to your CApp project by selecting <strong>New => Proxy Service </strong> from the Right click menu.  </p>
			<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Creating a Proxy Service using Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/creatingproxy0.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
		</p>
		<p>You can add Proxy Service <strong>File => New => Other => Proxy Service</strong> menu as well. If you follow that procedure, you will get a dialog box as shown in the following image.  </p>
			<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Creating a Proxy Service using Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/creatingproxy1.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
		</p>
		<p>Select <strong>Next</strong> and you will be forwarded to the next step. For both approaches described above, this step is same. Both approaches will bring you to this step.
		Provide a name for your Proxy Service for <strong>Name</strong>. For this example, specify the Proxy Service name as <strong>StockQuoteProxy</strong>.
		Select the <strong>New Proxy Service</strong> option from the option list and select <strong>Custom Proxy</strong> from the <strong>Drop Down List </strong>as shown in the image below. Finally 
		Click <strong>Next</strong>.</p>	
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Creating a Proxy Service using Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/creatingproxy2.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
		</p>	
		<p>You do not need to change any default settings in this dialog box. Click on <strong>Finish</strong>. </p>	
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Creating a Proxy Service using Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/creatingproxy3.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
		</p>		 
		<p>You have just added a Proxy Service with default configuration to your CApp project. If you have successfully followed the steps, you will get a CApp project as shown in the image below.</p>
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Creating a Proxy Service using Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/creatingproxy4.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
		</p>		
		<p>Now we move on to configure the <strong>Proxy Service</strong>  you have just added to your CApp project. First, <strong>Open StockQuoteProxy.xml</strong> by either double clicking on the <strong>StockQuoteProxy.xml</strong>
		file or selecting <strong>Open With => ESB Editor</strong> from right click menu. <strong>ESB Editor</strong> is a sophosticated Editor provided by WSO2 to edit <strong>ESB Artifacts</strong>
		 including <strong>Proxy Services, Sequences, etc</strong>. You will see the ESB editor as shown in the image below.
		</p>
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Creating a Proxy Service using Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/creatingproxy5.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
		</p>	
		<p>In order to configure the added Proxy Service, we use the <strong>Properties View</strong>. You can open the <strong>Properties View</strong> by either double clicking on the Items on the <strong>ESB Editor</strong> or 
		selecting <strong>Window => Show View => Properties</strong>. If you select the <strong>Root Element</strong> on the <strong>ESB Editor</strong>, you will see a set of configurable properties as shown in the image below.
		You can add/remove/chnage the <strong>Transports</strong> for your <strong>Proxy Service</strong> from there. You can enable Tracing and Statistics from there. If you need to change the QoS properties such as 
		<strong>Enabling Security </strong>and <strong>Reliable Messaging</strong>, you can change them from there. As discussed in the <a href="http://wso2.org/project/esb/java/2.1.0/docs/quickstart_guide.html#Proxy">original example</a>, we won't need to change any of the default
		settings shown for the Root element.</p>	
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Creating a Proxy Service using Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/creatingproxy6.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
		</p>
		<p>For a <strong>Proxy Service</strong> it requires a <strong>WSDL</strong>. Therefore, we first set the <strong>WDSL</strong> settings for the <strong>Proxy Service</strong>. Select <strong>WSDL</strong> in the <strong>ESB Editor</strong>.
		You will notice that the properties view will be changed when you select the <strong>WSDL</strong>. For the <strong>WSDL Type</strong> property, select <strong>Specify Source URL</strong> option from the dropdown list in the properties view.  
		</p>
			<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Creating a Proxy Service using Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/creatingproxy7.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
		</p>
		<p>When you setlect <strong>Specify Source URL</strong> at <strong> WSDL Type</strong>, another new property  will appear in the <strong>Properties View</strong> as <strong>WSDL URL</strong>. You can point to a <strong>WSDL</strong> in URI format here.
		It can be either a file  in the file system or a http url. For this example, we use a <strong>WSDL</strong> file stored in the file system. Therefore set <strong>file:repository/samples/resources/proxy/sample_proxy_1.wsdl</strong> as the <strong>WSDL URL</strong>.
		</p>
			<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Creating a Proxy Service using Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/creatingproxy8.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
		</p>
		<p>Now you have successfully configured the <strong>WSDL</strong> and now we move on to configure the <strong>EndPoint</strong>. As explained in the <a href="http://wso2.org/project/esb/java/3.0.1/docs/quickstart_guide.html#Proxy">original example</a>, here we use an <strong>Address End point</strong>.
		In default configuration, there are no end points related to a <strong>Proxy Service </strong>. Therefore we manually add an address end point by selecting <strong>New Child => End Point[Address](Anonymous) </strong> from the right click menu of the <strong>Endpoint</strong> item of the <strong>Proxy Service</strong>.  
		</p>
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Creating a Proxy Service using Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/creatingproxy9.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br> 
		</p>
		<p>Now you have completed configuring the <strong>End Point</strong> and we move on to configuring the <strong>InSequence</strong> of the <strong>Proxy Service</strong>. There exist a <strong>Log Mediator</strong> in the <strong>InSequence</strong>. But in this example we don't need it. Therefore we set the <strong>Sequence Type</strong>  as <strong>None</strong>
		from the <strong>Properties View</strong>. Then the existing <strong>Log Mediator</strong> will be removed from it.  
		</p>
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Creating a Proxy Service using Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/creatingproxy10.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br> 
		</p>
		<p>Now that you have successfully completed configuring the <strong>InSequence</strong>, now it is time to configure the <strong>OutSequence</strong>. First, change the <strong>Sequence Type</strong> value in the <strong>Properties View</strong> to <strong>Anonymous</strong>. Then select the <strong>OutSequence</strong> and select <strong>New Child => Sequence (Anonymous)</strong> from the right click menu. 
		</p>		
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Creating a Proxy Service using Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/creatingproxy11.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br> 
		</p>
		<p>Now select <strong>Sequence (Anonymous)</strong> and then right click on it and select <strong>New Child => Core => Send</strong>. This adds a <strong>Send Mediator</strong> to your <strong>OutSequence</strong>. This is shown in the image below.
		</p>
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Creating a Proxy Service using Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/creatingproxy12.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br> 
		</p>
		<p> Now you have completed configuring the <strong>Proxy Service</strong> for the ESB. In the nexet section  let's see how we can create a connection to a WSO2 Carbon Based ESB placed in your <strong>Local File System</strong>. 
		</p>
		<h2 id="AddingaWSO2CarbonBasedServertotheDeveloperStudioIDE">Adding a WSO2 Carbon Based Server to the Developer Studio IDE.</h2>
		<br></br>
		<p> When you install the <strong>Developer Studio</strong>, a new view called <strong>Servers</strong> appear in the IDE. All the existing server applications such as Apache Tomcat, WSO2 WSAS, WSO2 ESB, etc can be integrated to the IDE from there so that these server instances can be managed from the IDE itself. In this example we will show integrating <strong>WSO2 ESB</strong> to the IDE.  
		First open the <strong>Servers View</strong> and right click on it and select <strong>New => Server</strong> from it.
		</p>
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Adding a WSO2 Carbon Based Server to the Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/creatingserver1.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br> 
		</p>
		<p> Then you will get a new Dialog Box where you can sprcify the Sevrer instance and configure it. In this Dialog Box, select <strong>WSO2 => WSO2 Carbon 3.0.1 Serve</strong> for <strong>Server Type</strong>. Then you need to mention the <strong>Server Host Name</strong>. By default the value is <strong>localhost</strong> and you need <strong>not</strong> to change it. In the place where 
		you can specify the <strong>Server Name</strong>, you  can type a name for the server or keep the default name. In the <strong>Server Runtime Environment</strong>, you have to point to the Server instance where it resides in the <strong>local file system</strong>. In order to do that click on <strong>Add</strong> hyperlink next to the text box.
		</p>
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Adding a WSO2 Carbon Based Server to the Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/creatingserver3.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br> 
		</p>
		<p>When you click on the <strong>Add</strong> hyperlink as we mentioned above, you will get a new Dialog Box where you can point to the ESB instance in the file System. From this Dialog Box, you need to configure the <strong>Carbon Home</strong> which is the Server instance in the local file system. 
		</p>
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Adding a WSO2 Carbon Based Server to the Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/creatingserver4.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>  
		</p>
		<p> To configure that click on the <strong>Browse</strong> button and you will get a file system browser and from there you need to select the <strong>Root</strong> folder of the ESB instance in the file system.
		</p>
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Adding a WSO2 Carbon Based Server to the Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/creatingserver5.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>  
		</p>
		<p>Select the <strong>Root</strong> directory of the ESB instance and click on <strong>OK</strong> button. Then the selected path will be set as the <strong>Carbon Home</strong>. 
		</p>
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Adding a WSO2 Carbon Based Server to the Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/creatingserver6.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>  
		</p>
		<p> Now click on <strong>Finish</strong> button and finish the integrating the Server instances to the IDE. Then there will be a ESB instance integrateed to the IDE as shown in the image below.
		</p>
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Adding a WSO2 Carbon Based Server to the Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/creatingserver7.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>  
		</p>
		
		<h2 id="StartingtheWSO2CarbonBasedServerfromtheDeveloperStudioIDE">Starting the WSO2 Carbon Based ESB from the Developer Studio IDE</h2>
		<p>Now you have integrated the ESB instance to the IDE, we look at how to start the ESB instance from the Developer Studio IDE. There are 2 methods to do that from the Developer Studio. If you select 
		the ESB instance in the <strong>Servers View</strong>, you will notice that there is a <strong>Start</strong> icon in the <strong>top right corner</strong>. Else you can right click on the ESB instance 
		and select <strong>Start</strong> from there. 
		</p>
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Starting the WSO2 Carbon Based ESB from the Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/startingserver1.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>  
		</p>
		<p>When you start the ESB from the IDE, there will be service logs shown in the console of the IDE. These log messages are identocal to the messages you get when you invoke the ESB from the platform console.
		</p>
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Starting the WSO2 Carbon Based ESB from the Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/startingserver2.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>  
		</p>
		<p> If you have successfully started the ESB, ESB Web Console will be opened in the Brwoser automatically. Use default credentials for WSO2 prducts (<strong>Username=admin and Password=admin</strong>) to log in to the ESB Web console.
		</p> 
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Starting the WSO2 Carbon Based ESB from the Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/serverstarted1.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>  
		</p>
		<p>When you log in to the system, ESB dash board will appear as shown below. This means you have successfully managed to start the <strong>ESB</strong> from the <strong>Developer Studio</strong> IDE. 
		</p>
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Starting the WSO2 Carbon Based ESB from the Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/serverstarted2.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>  
		</p>
		
		<h2 id="DeployingthecretedProxyServiceintheserverinstanceusingDeveloperStudioIDE">Deploying the creted Proxy Service in the server instance using Developer Studio IDE</h2>
		<p>Now we look at how can we deploy the created <strong>Proxy Service</strong> using the <strong>Developer Studio</strong> IDE. First check what are the existing Services in the ESB from the Web console by selecting <strong>List</strong> under <strong>Services</strong> section in the left panel.
		</p>
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Deploying the creted Proxy Service in the server instance using Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/deployingservice1.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>  
		</p>
		<p>The <strong>Proxy Service</strong> we created was <strong>StockQuoteProxy</strong> and it is not currently deployed in the ESB as a service. In order to deploy the created service right click on the cretaed CApp project and select <strong>Run As => Run on Server</strong>. efore trying to deploy the service, you <strong>must</strong>
		start the ESB as we described in the above section.
		</p>
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Deploying the creted Proxy Service in the server instance using Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/deployingservice2.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>  
		</p>
		<p>Then a new Dialog Box will appear and it will show what are the currently running WSO2 Carbon based server instances such as WSO2 WSAS, WSO2 ESB, etc. From that list, select WSO2 ESB instance which you have deployed and click <strong>Finish</strong>.
		</p>
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Deploying the creted Proxy Service in the server instance using Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/deployingservice3.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>  
		</p>
		<p>Now you have asked Developer Studio IDE to deply your <strong>Proxy Service</strong> in the WSO2 ESB and it will do it for you. There will be log messages appear in the Developer Studio Console about the progress of that deployment.
		 By reading those messages you will be able to identify whether your <strong>Proxy Service </strong> is successfully deployed or not.
		</p>
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Deploying the creted Proxy Service in the server instance using Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/deployingservice4.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>  
		</p>
		<p>If your <strong>Proxy Service </strong>is successfully deployed in the WSO2 ESB, you can go to the WSO2 ESB web console and check what are the existing service by selecting <strong>List</strong> under <strong>Service</strong> section in the left panel. 
		If the deployment is successful, your <strong>StockQuoteProxy</strong> will appear in this list as shown in the image below.
		</p>
		<p>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			<img alt="Deploying the creted Proxy Service in the server instance using Developer Studio IDE" src="images/samples/esb/deployingservice5.png"></img>
			<br></br>
			<br></br>  
		</p>
		<p>Follow the procedure starting from <strong>Starting the Sample Apache Axis2 Server</strong> described in the <a href="http://wso2.org/project/esb/java/3.0.1/docs/quickstart_guide.html#Proxy">original sample</a> to run the service and utilize it.</p>
	</body>
</html> 
   
